<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://womanonrails.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://womanonrails.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2021-06-23T17:02:13-04:00</updated><id>https://womanonrails.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Woman on Rails</title><author><name>womanonrails</name></author><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Test doubles - the difference between stubs and mocks</title><link href="https://womanonrails.com/test-doubles" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test doubles - the difference between stubs and mocks" /><published>2021-06-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-06-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://womanonrails.com/test-doubles</id><author><name>womanonrails</name></author><category term="testing" /><category term="tdd" /><category term="tests" /><category term="mocks" /><category term="stubs" /><summary type="html">In the testing world, we have stubs, mocks, dummy objects, and so on. It can be confusing what to use and when to use it. I would like to organize all of those terms in a more accessible way. There is one problem. In many different sources, we have discrepancies regards to those terms. I will show you my understanding of this topic. Of course, based on chosen sources.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Dynamic configuration using YAML in Ruby</title><link href="https://womanonrails.com/dynamic-yaml-configuration" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dynamic configuration using YAML in Ruby" /><published>2021-03-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://womanonrails.com/dynamic-yaml-configuration</id><author><name>womanonrails</name></author><category term="programming" /><category term="TIL" /><category term="Ruby" /><category term="Ruby on Rails" /><summary type="html">From time to time using Ruby or even more often using Ruby on Rails, I need additional configuration with some secret API keys. I don’t want to save those data in the git repository, but it is too early to put them in the database. In this case, environment variables can do the trick. You put sensitive data to the .env file, and you don’t track this file in the git repository. We’re done! Not exactly, in my case. I wanted to have the structured data in one file. So I used the environment variable together with YAML (recursive acronym from words YAML Ain’t Markup Language) file and ERB (Embedded Ruby). Let me show you how this looks like.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">How to focus as a programmer?</title><link href="https://womanonrails.com/how-to-focus" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to focus as a programmer?" /><published>2021-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://womanonrails.com/how-to-focus</id><author><name>womanonrails</name></author><category term="work" /><category term="30devstories" /><category term="career" /><category term="health" /><summary type="html">In times of full connections and online life, we have a problem staying focused. We need to focus, to feel the flow. One of the most important feelings in our work time. Flow is the mental state in which we do some activity fully immersed and engaged in the process of the activity. It’s a very positive and energized feeling, which brings us a lot of satisfaction. But how can we have flow in a world full of distractions? Now, since a lot of us work from home, the situation can be even more challenging. This time, I would like to share with you some of my tips, which help me to stay focus and experience more flow.</summary></entry></feed>